### BERTRAND DUBAUT

### SOFTWARE ENGINEER - RUBY DEVELOPER

bdubaut@gmail.com +61 481 755 342 LinkedIn Github Twitter

I'm a French software engineer living in Brisbane, Australia. I am 28, speak fluent English, and have a Master's degree in Computer Science from one of the top French Computer Engineering schools.

I am a ruby developer (Ruby on Rails, Grape API...) with strong software and cloud architecture skills. I am an Elixir enthusiast (functional programming), and keen to further my skills with front-end technologies like React or Relay.

My technology monitoring skills, up to date with the current state of our industry, will be appreciated. On a personal note, I have played baseball my whole life, including one year of college Baseball in California. I now play competitive Baseball and coach a youth team here in Brisbane in my spare time.

### SKILLS

PROGRAMMING RUBY RUBY ON RAILS GRAPE API FRAMEWORK ELIXIR JAVA JAVASCRIPT COFFEESCRIPT JQUERY HTML 5 CSS

DATABASES MYSQL POSTGRESQL MONGODB REDIS ORMS ACTIVERECORD MONGOID

**CLOUD AWS S3 REDSHIFT EC2** 

PROJECT AGILE PROJECT MANAGEMENT GITHUB FLOW

## **EMPLOYMENT**

Software Engineer - Ruby developper, Everydayhero

2015-08 — 2016-03

Everydayhero is a crowdfunding platform aimed at charity fundraising.

Ruby Ruby on Rails Elixir PostgreSQL React AWS

Software Engineer, Oomph

2014-09 — 2015-07

Oomph is a platform for publishers and advertisers allowing them to create digital magazines or ads for mobile devices and tablets.

Ruby Ruby on Rails AWS PostgreSQL

Software Engineer, Visibleo

2014-01 — 2014-07

Visibleo is a web-marketing start-up based in the Paris Suburbs. They perform Facebook Ads and Google AdWords campaigns, while also creating websites for their clients. In charge of creating and developing

web applications for the IT department of the company.

Ruby Ruby on Rails AWS Grape API JQuery MongoDB

#### Technical Project Manager/Developer, Reputation Squad

2013-02 — 2013-09

Reputation Squad is an E-Reputation agency in Paris: the company manages and monitors its clients' reputation on the Internet. In charge of creating and developing web and social media monitoring tools for the agency

Ruby on Rails PHP Perl Facebook API Twitter API Project Management

#### Technical consultant / Developer, Sogeti

2011-02 — 2013-02

Consultant in projects for several large-scale French companies like Air France or Renault.

Managed a developer team based in India from France

Java/J2EE Oracle SQL HP Quality Center QuickTest Pro Visual Basic

# PROJECTS

#### Adomatic

Solution to convert an existing print Ad inventory into engaging rich media Ads for tablet and mobile.

Ruby on Rails PostgreSQL AWS

#### Global Sourcing Renault

In charge of a vehicle selling application for RENAULT's employees (as a consultant with Sogeti). Technical specifications, and management of an Off-Shore development team in India. Also testing, deployement actions, bug management.

Java/J2EE Oracle SQL WebSphere

#### Air France Check-In

Development and maintenance of a test automaton for the new passenger check-in system for Air France and SkyTeam (KLM, Alitalia....). Discussions with the KLM dev team to help them develop their own automaton. The automaton was designed to take over every interface (Desk, Internet portal, self check-in).

HP Quick Test Pro Visual Basic

#### Paris Universite Club Baseball web app

Design, implementation, deployment of a web app for the Paris Baseball Softball and Cricket club. Providing blogs, emails and player management tools for the amateur club

Ruby on Rails Devise Heroku Mandrill Refills/Bitters RSS Ghost

### **EDUCATION**

Master's degree of computer science and software engineering, Ecole advanced C 2011-09 — 2013-06 des Technologies Numeriques Appliquees programming Java PHP

Ruby .NET Object-Oriented programming

Bachelor's degree of computer science and software engineering, Ecole des Technologies Numeriques Appliquees

Shell C programming PHP MySQL UNIX

2010-09 — 2011-06

System Administration Networks

Undergraduate studies, Universite Paris VI

C Programming Linear 2009-09 — 2010-06

Algebra Algorithms OCaml

Undergraduate studies, Merced Community College

Baseball English Political 2008-09 — 2009-06

Science Chemistry Calculus

## **AFFILIATION**

Player, Youth Coach, Team Captain, Paris Universite Club Baseball

1995-09 — 2015-08

This is the club I grew up with, playing, coaching the kids, and ultimately being the club captain of the first team of Paris' baseball club.

Player, Youth Coach, Windsor Royals Baseball Club

2015-09 — Present

Playing competitive baseball for the best club in Brisbane, and teaching the game to the younger generation.

*Instructor*, Brisbane Baseball Academy

2015-10 — Present

Teaching Brisbane's top baseball talent how to improve their game.

Member, Merced Blue Devils Alumni Association

2010-01 — Present

## REFERENCES

Contact details will be provided if requested.

*Jasmyn Mason*, HR manager Jasmyn is the HR manager for EverydayHero.

Ryan Booker, Ruby/iOS developer

Ryan and I worked together for Oomph and EverydayHero.

Valerie Abbot, QA Manager

Valerie hired me to work for Oomph when I first arrived in Australia.

### INTERESTS

Baseball Current

The sport I have played all my life

Mixology Current

Making cocktails is an advanced hobby of mine. It's just like cooking or baking, only I like to create sophisticated beverages.

History Current

Learning about the History of all cultures is something that interests me a whole lot.

Music Current

I played the piano at the Conservatorium when I was young. Now I am learning Ukulele because it's easier to carry around.

Reading Current

Traveling Current

# LANGUAGES

French Mothertongue

*English* Bilingual